pcpartpicker.com 2018-12-31

# Privacy Policy - PCPartPicker

## Quick human readable summary

  * We don’t share your personal information with anyone except to comply with the law, develop our products, or protect our rights.
  * We store your email for account logins, password resets, and opt-in-only notification/price-drop emails.
  * We don’t send unsolicited email, nor do we share your email address with third parties.
  * We store your IP address for legitimate interests, specifically: security, spam prevention, and fraud detection.
  * We request your consent when required by law to store or process personally identifying information that is not essential to the operation of our website.
  * Your current consent status is: NOT SPECIFIED. You may provide or revoke your consent at any time.

## Introduction

We are committed to safeguarding the privacy of our website visitors and service users.

This policy applies where we are acting as a data controller with respect to the personal data of our website visitors and service users; in other words, where we determine the purposes and means of the processing of that personal data.

We use cookies on our website. Insofar as those cookies are not strictly necessary for the provision of our website and services, we will ask you to consent to our use of cookies when you first visit our website.

Our website incorporates opt-in email controls which affect how we will process your personal data. By using the controls, you can specify whether you would like to receive direct email communications such as comment reply notifications or price drop notifications. You can access the controls via your account preferences.

In this policy, "we", "us" and "our" refer to PCPartPicker.

## How we use your personal data

In this section we have set out: 

  * the general categories of personal data that we may process;
  * the purposes for which we may process personal data; and
  * the legal bases of the processing.

We may process data about your use of our website and services ("usage data"). The usage data may include your IP address, geographical location, browser type and version, operating system, referral source, length of visit, page views and website navigation paths, as well as information about the timing, frequency and pattern of your service use. The source of the usage data is our analytics tracking system. This usage data may be processed for the purposes of analysing the use of the website and services. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely monitoring and improving our website and services, security, and fraud prevention.

We may process your account data ("account data"). The account data may include your email address. The source of your account data is you. The account data may be processed for the purposes of operating our website, providing our services, ensuring the security of our website and services, maintaining back-ups of our databases and communicating with you. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely the proper administration of our website and business.

We may process your information included in your personal profile on our website ("profile data"). The profile data may include your email address, profile pictures. The profile data may be processed for the purposes of enabling and monitoring your use of our website and services. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely the proper administration of our website and business.

We may process your personal data that are provided in the course of the use of our services ("service data"). The service data may include your IP address. The source of the service data is you. The service data may be processed for the purposes of operating our website, providing our services, ensuring the security of our website and services, maintaining back-ups of our databases and communicating with you. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely the proper administration of our website and business, security, and fraud prevention.

We may process information that you post for publication on our website or through our services ("publication data"). The publication data may be processed for the purposes of enabling such publication and administering our website and services. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely the proper administration of our website and business.

We may process information relating to transactions, including clickthroughs to retailers or partners through our website ("transaction data"). The transaction data may be processed for the purpose of aggregating usage statistics, security, and fraud prevention. The legal basis for this processing is the proper administration of our website and business.

We may process information that you provide to us for the purpose of subscribing to our email notifications and/or newsletters ("notification data"). The notification data may be processed for the purposes of sending you the relevant notifications. The legal basis for this processing is consent.

We may process information contained in or relating to any communication that you send to us ("correspondence data"). The correspondence data may include the communication content and metadata associated with the communication. Our website will generate the metadata associated with communications made using the website contact forms. The correspondence data may be processed for the purposes of communicating with you and record-keeping. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely the proper administration of our website and business and communications with users.

We may process any of your personal data identified in this policy where necessary for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims, whether in court proceedings or in an administrative or out-of-court procedure. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely the protection and assertion of our legal rights, your legal rights and the legal rights of others.

We may process any of your personal data identified in this policy where necessary for the purposes of obtaining or maintaining insurance coverage, managing risks, or obtaining professional advice. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely the proper protection of our business against risks.

In addition to the specific purposes for which we may process your personal data set out in this Section 2, we may also process any of your personal data where such processing is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject, or in order to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person.

Please do not supply any other person's personal data to us, unless we prompt you to do so.

## Automated decision-making

We will use your personal data for the purposes of automated decision-making in relation to security, spam prevention, and fraud detection.

This automated decision-making will involve usage pattern analysis to detect malicious behavior, spam, or violations of our Terms of Service or User Code of Conduct.

The significance and possible consequences of this automated decision-making are warning notifications, the banning of your account, or the banning of your usage our website.

## Providing your personal data to others

We may disclose your personal data where such disclosure is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject, or in order to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person. We may also disclose your personal data where such disclosure is necessary for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims, whether in court proceedings or in an administrative or out-of-court procedure.

## International transfers of your personal data

In this Section 5, we provide information about the circumstances in which your personal data may be transferred to countries outside the European Economic Area (EEA).

We have offices and facilities in the United States. Transfers will be protected by appropriate safeguards, namely the use of standard data protection clauses adopted or approved by the European Commission, a copy of which can be obtained [here](https://www.eugdpr.org/).

The hosting facilities for our website are situated in the United States. Transfers will be protected by appropriate safeguards, namely the use of standard data protection clauses adopted or approved by the European Commission, a copy of which you can obtain [here](https://www.eugdpr.org/).

You acknowledge that personal data that you submit for publication through our website or services may be available, via the internet, around the world. We cannot prevent the use (or misuse) of such personal data by others.

## Retaining and deleting personal data

This Section 6 sets out our data retention policies and procedure, which are designed to help ensure that we comply with our legal obligations in relation to the retention and deletion of personal data.

Personal data that we process for any purpose or purposes shall not be kept for longer than is necessary for that purpose or those purposes.

We will retain your email addresses for a minimum period of 1 day following the deletion of the account, and for a maximum period of 30 days following the deletion of the account.

In some cases it is not possible for us to specify in advance the periods for which your personal data will be retained. In such cases, we will determine the period of retention based on the following criteria: 

  * the period of retention of ip addresses will be determined based on the requirements of website security, spam prevention, and fraud prevention.

Notwithstanding the other provisions of this Section 6, we may retain your personal data where such retention is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject, or in order to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person.

## Security of personal data

We will take appropriate technical and organisational precautions to secure your personal data and to prevent the loss, misuse or alteration of your personal data.

We will store all your personal data on secure servers.

The following personal data will be stored by us in encrypted form: password(s).

Data relating to your enquiries and transactions that is sent from your web browser to our web server, or from our web server to your web browser, will be protected using encryption technology.

You acknowledge that the transmission of unencrypted (or inadequately encrypted) data over the internet is inherently insecure, and we cannot guarantee the security of data sent over the internet.

You should ensure that your password is not susceptible to being guessed, whether by a person or a computer program. You are responsible for keeping the password you use for accessing our website confidential and we will not ask you for your password (except when you log in to our website, change your password, or change your email address).

## Amendments

We may update this policy from time to time by publishing a new version on our website.

You should check this page occasionally to ensure you are happy with any changes to this policy.

We may notify you of significant changes to this policy by email or through announcements on our website.

## Your rights

In this Section 9, we have summarised the rights that you have under data protection law. Some of the rights are complex, and not all of the details have been included in our summaries. Accordingly, you should read the relevant laws and guidance from the regulatory authorities for a full explanation of these rights.

Your principal rights under data protection law are: 

  * the right to access;
  * the right to rectification;
  * the right to erasure;
  * the right to restrict processing;
  * the right to object to processing;
  * the right to data portability;
  * the right to complain to a supervisory authority; and
  * the right to withdraw consent.

You have the right to confirmation as to whether or not we process your personal data and, where we do, access to the personal data, together with certain additional information. That additional information includes details of the purposes of the processing, the categories of personal data concerned and the recipients of the personal data. Providing the rights and freedoms of others are not affected, we will supply to you a copy of your personal data. The first copy will be provided free of charge, but additional copies may be subject to a reasonable fee. You can request your personal data by emailing dpo@pcpartpicker.com.

You have the right to have any inaccurate personal data about you rectified and, taking into account the purposes of the processing, to have any incomplete personal data about you completed.

In some circumstances you have the right to the erasure of your personal data without undue delay. Those circumstances include: the personal data are no longer necessary in relation to the purposes for which they were collected or otherwise processed; you withdraw consent to consent-based processing; you object to the processing under certain rules of applicable data protection law; the processing is for direct marketing purposes; and the personal data have been unlawfully processed. However, there are exclusions of the right to erasure. The general exclusions include where processing is necessary: for exercising the right of freedom of expression and information; for compliance with a legal obligation; or for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims.

In some circumstances you have the right to restrict the processing of your personal data. Those circumstances are: you contest the accuracy of the personal data; processing is unlawful but you oppose erasure; we no longer need the personal data for the purposes of our processing, but you require personal data for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims; and you have objected to processing, pending the verification of that objection. Where processing has been restricted on this basis, we may continue to store your personal data. However, we will only otherwise process it: with your consent; for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims; for the protection of the rights of another natural or legal person; or for reasons of important public interest.

You have the right to object to our processing of your personal data on grounds relating to your particular situation, but only to the extent that the legal basis for the processing is that the processing is necessary for: the performance of a task carried out in the public interest or in the exercise of any official authority vested in us; or the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by us or by a third party. If you make such an objection, we will cease to process the personal information unless we can demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for the processing which override your interests, rights and freedoms, or the processing is for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims.

You have the right to object to our processing of your personal data for direct marketing purposes (including profiling for direct marketing purposes). If you make such an objection, we will cease to process your personal data for this purpose.

You have the right to object to our processing of your personal data for scientific or historical research purposes or statistical purposes on grounds relating to your particular situation, unless the processing is necessary for the performance of a task carried out for reasons of public interest.

To the extent that the legal basis for our processing of your personal data is: 

  * consent; or
  * that the processing is necessary for the performance of a contract to which you are party or in order to take steps at your request prior to entering into a contract, and such processing is carried out by automated means, you have the right to receive your personal data from us in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format. However, this right does not apply where it would adversely affect the rights and freedoms of others.

If you consider that our processing of your personal information infringes data protection laws, you have a legal right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority responsible for data protection. You may do so in the EU member state of your habitual residence, your place of work or the place of the alleged infringement.

To the extent that the legal basis for our processing of your personal information is consent, you have the right to withdraw that consent at any time. Withdrawal will not affect the lawfulness of processing before the withdrawal.

You may exercise any of your rights in relation to your personal data by written notice to us.

## Third party websites

Our website includes hyperlinks to, and details of, third party websites.

We have no control over, and are not responsible for, the privacy policies and practices of third parties.

## Personal data of children

Our website and services are targeted at persons at least the age of 13.

If we have reason to believe that we hold personal data of a person under that age in our databases, we will delete that personal data.

## Updating information

Please let us know if the personal information that we hold about you needs to be corrected or updated.

## About cookies

A cookie is a file containing an identifier (a string of letters and numbers) that is sent by a web server to a web browser and is stored by the browser. The identifier is then sent back to the server each time the browser requests a page from the server.

Cookies may be either "persistent" cookies or "session" cookies: a persistent cookie will be stored by a web browser and will remain valid until its set expiry date, unless deleted by the user before the expiry date; a session cookie, on the other hand, will expire at the end of the user session, when the web browser is closed.

Cookies do not typically contain any information that personally identifies a user, but personal information that we store about you may be linked to the information stored in and obtained from cookies.

## Cookies that we use

We use cookies for the following purposes: 

  * authentication - we use cookies to identify you when you visit our website and as you navigate our website (cookies used for this purpose are: xsessionid);
  * status - we use cookies to help us to determine if you are logged into our website (cookies used for this purpose are: xsessionid);
  * part list - we use cookies to maintain the state of your part list as you navigate our website (cookies used for this purpose are: xsessionid);
  * part list history - we use cookies to maintain the list of changes to your part list as you navigate our website (cookies used for this purpose are: xsessionid);
  * personalisation - we use cookies to store information about your preferences and to personalise our website for you (cookies used for this purpose are: xsessionid);
  * security - we use cookies as an element of the security measures used to protect user accounts, including preventing fraudulent use of login credentials, and to protect our website and services generally (cookies used for this purpose are: xsessionid, xcsrftoken);
  * analysis - we use cookies to help us to analyse the use and performance of our website and services (cookies used for this purpose are: xsessiionid, __utma, __utmb, __utmc, __utmt, __utmv, __utmz); and
  * cookie consent - we use cookies to store your preferences in relation to the use of cookies more generally (cookies used for this purpose are: xgdpr-consent).

## Cookies used by our service providers

Our service providers use cookies and those cookies may be stored on your computer when you visit our website.

We use Google Analytics to analyse the use of our website. Google Analytics gathers information about website use by means of cookies. The information gathered relating to our website is used to create reports about the use of our website. Google's privacy policy is available at: <https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/>.

## Managing cookies

Most browsers allow you to refuse to accept cookies and to delete cookies. The methods for doing so vary from browser to browser, and from version to version. You can however obtain up-to-date information about blocking and deleting cookies via these links: 

  * https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?hl=en (Chrome);
  * https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-and-disable-cookies-website-preferences (Firefox);
  * https://www.opera.com/help/tutorials/security/cookies/ (Opera);
  * https://support.microsoft.com/en-gb/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies (Internet Explorer);
  * https://support.apple.com/kb/PH21411 (Safari); and
  * https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-10-microsoft-edge-and-privacy (Edge).

Blocking all cookies will have a negative impact upon the usability of many websites.

If you block cookies, you will not be able to use all the features on our website.

## Cookie preferences

You can manage your preferences relating to the use of cookies on our website by clicking here.

## Our details

This website is owned and operated by PCPartPicker, LLC.

We are a United States Limited Liability Corporation registered in the state of Texas.

Our principal place of business is at 105 South Blair Street, Round Rock, TX, 78664.

You can contact us: 

  * by mail, to the postal address given above;
  * by email, using [support@pcpartpicker.com](mailto:support@pcpartpicker.com).

Your privacy is important to us. At PCPartPicker we have a few fundamental principles:

  * We don’t ask you for personal information unless we truly need it.
  * We don’t share your personal information with anyone except to comply with the law, develop our products, or protect our rights.
  * We don’t send unsolicited email, nor do we share your email address with third parties.
  * We don’t store personal information on our servers unless required for the on-going operation of one of our services.

PCPartPicker, LLC (“PCPartPicker”) operates pcpartpicker.com. It is PCPartPicker’s policy to respect your privacy regarding any information we may collect while operating our website.

## Website Visitors

Like most website operators, PCPartPicker collects non-personally-identifying information of the sort that web browsers and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, language preference, referring site, and the date and time of each visitor request. PCPartPicker’s purpose in collecting non-personally identifying information is to better understand how PCPartPicker’s visitors use its website. From time to time, PCPartPicker may release non-personally-identifying information in the aggregate, e.g., by publishing a report on trends in the usage of its website. 

PCPartPicker also collects potentially personally-identifying information like Internet Protocol (IP) addresses for logged in users and for users leaving comments on the PCPartPicker website. PCPartPicker only discloses logged in user and commenter IP addresses under the same circumstances that it uses and discloses personally-identifying information as described below, except that IP addresses are visible and disclosed to the administrators of the PCPartPicker website. 

## Gathering of Personally-Identifying Information

Certain visitors to PCPartPicker’s websites choose to interact with PCPartPicker in ways that require PCPartPicker to gather personally-identifying information. The amount and type of information that PCPartPicker gathers depends on the nature of the interaction. For example, we ask visitors who sign up for an account at the PCPartPicker website to provide a username and email address. PCPartPicker collects such information only insofar as is necessary or appropriate to fulfill the purpose of the visitor’s interaction with PCPartPicker. PCPartPicker does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below. And visitors can always refuse to supply personally-identifying information, with the caveat that it may prevent them from engaging in certain website-related activities. 

## Aggregated Statistics

PCPartPicker may collect statistics about the behavior of visitors to its websites. PCPartPicker may display this information publicly or provide it to others. However, PCPartPicker does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below. 

## Protection of Certain Personally-Identifying Information

PCPartPicker discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only to those of its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations that (i) need to know that information in order to process it on PCPartPicker’s behalf or to provide services available at PCPartPicker’s website, and (ii) that have agreed not to disclose it to others. Some of those employees, contractors and affiliated organizations may be located outside of your home country; by using PCPartPicker’s website, you consent to the transfer of such information to them. PCPartPicker will not rent or sell potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information to anyone. Other than to its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations, as described above, PCPartPicker discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only in response to a subpoena, court order or other governmental request, or when PCPartPicker believes in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the property or rights of PCPartPicker, third parties or the public at large. PCPartPicker takes all measures reasonably necessary to protect against the unauthorized access, use, alteration or destruction of potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information. 

## Cookies

A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor’s computer, and that the visitor’s browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. PCPartPicker uses cookies to help PCPartPicker identify and track visitors, their usage of PCPartPicker website, and their website access preferences. PCPartPicker visitors who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers should set their browsers to refuse cookies before using PCPartPicker’s websites, with the drawback that certain features of PCPartPicker’s websites may not function properly without the aid of cookies. 

## Business Transfers

If PCPartPicker, or substantially all of its assets were acquired, or in the unlikely event that PCPartPicker goes out of business or enters bankruptcy, user information would be one of the assets that is transferred or acquired by a third party. You acknowledge that such transfers may occur, and that any acquirer of PCPartPicker may continue to use your personal information as set forth in this policy. 

## Privacy Policy Changes

Although most changes are likely to be minor, PCPartPicker may change its Privacy Policy from time to time, and in PCPartPicker’s sole discretion. PCPartPicker encourages visitors to frequently check this page for any changes to its Privacy Policy. Your continued use of this site after any change in this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such change.
